RAPHAEL DO NASCIMENTO BORGES

São Bernardo do Campo - SP

E-mail: raphael.n.borges@gmail.com | Celular: +55 (11) 99017-3638 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/raphael-do-nascimento-borges/

GitHub: https://github.com/rapha-borges/

Site: https://r11s.com.br/

SUMMARY

Student of Analysis and Systems Development at Uninter. I hold certifications as an AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner and Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations Associate, and I am mentored by Mateus Prado, an AWS TAM. With over 15 years of experience in Linux systems. I have actively participated in open-source projects. Currently, my focus is on specializing in Containers and Kubernetes through the LINUXtips Intensive Program in Containers and Kubernetes (PICK). My expertise encompasses network infrastructure, cloud services, container orchestration, complemented by practical experience in software development and database management.

EDUCATION

Associate Degree: Technology in Analysis and Systems Development - Uninter 2024

LANGUAGES

English - Intermediate Level French - Basic Level Portuguese - Native

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Staff Burger

Owner | October 2020 - February 2022 | Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Entrepreneurial journey as Owner of Staff Burger, steering the ship from October 2020 to February 2022. I was responsible for the whole business, from the conception of the idea to the execution.

Picanha Catering

Assistant | July 2018 - August 2019 | Luxembourg, Luxembourg

At Picanha Catering in Luxembourg, I served as an assistant from July 2018 to August 2019, overseeing seamless event organization, providing dedicated customer support, efficiently troubleshooting issues, and assisting in strategic procurement of essential supplies.

Grupo Contax

Technical Support | July 2013 - April 2015 | Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

As a Technical Support professional at Contax in Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil, I excelled in addressing critical customer issues previously handled by other departments. I engaged in direct communication with managers and leaders of technical teams in the serviced regions, while monitoring and resolving critical and impactful cases.

COURSES AND ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCES

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Amazon Web Services (AWS) - 2023
Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Certified Foundations Associate - 2023
AWS Expert - LINUXTips - 34 hours - 2022
Demystifying Docker - LINUXTips - 12 hours - 2022
Python for Web Development - Alura - 85 hours - 2022
Python Enthusiast - Hashtag Treinamentos - 100 hours - 2022
Microsoft S2B Network and Systems Administration - PUC-RS - 2010

PUBLICATIONS

<u>A custom action to deploy mdBook #githubhack2023</u> on dev.to - May 2023 <u>A Fast, Secure, and Scalable Recursive DNS Server (pt-br)</u> on dev.to - Jul 2023 Have you heard about Digestabot? (pt-br) on dev.to - Dec 2023

SKILLS

Containers and Orchestration: Kubernetes, Docker

Cloud and IaC: AWS, OCI, Terraform

Observability: Prometheus

Development: Python, Bash Script, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

CI/CD: Git, GitHub Actions

Network Infrastructure and Security:

- DNS (Domain Name System)
- OSI model (Open System Interconnection)
- Communication and Security Protocols (HTTP, HTTPS, TCP/IP, UDP, Stateful, Stateless)
- Load Balancer
- Firewall
- VPN (Virtual Private Network)
- CDN (Content Delivery Network)

Hardware and Operating Systems: Linux, macOS, Windows